psagroup.com 2015-12-19

# Privacy Policy | PSA

##  PSA Privacy Statement

####  July 2014  
PSA Global Privacy Statement: Effective July 01, 2014

This privacy statement applies to psagroup.com and all PSA websites, services and products that collect or process data and display these terms. It does not apply to any PSA site, service or product that does not display or link to this statement or that contains its own separate privacy statement.

Pacific Strategies and Assessments (PSA) is committed to protecting your privacy including protection against loss, misuse and alteration of data stored and process by PSA.

This Privacy Policy is designed to describe how we secure and maintain our client’s personal information and any information given to us will never be sold, rented, traded, shared or leased other than as outlined in this Policy.

PSA does not publish text, images, or multimedia content that portray nudity, foul language, violence or other information not suitable for children and PSA will not knowingly collect or maintain personally identifiable information from or about anyone under 13. PSA is committed to complying with privacy laws to which it is subject and adhering to the highest industry standards for privacy including adhering voluntarily to EU privacy laws.

####    
Collection and Use of Information

PSA collects different kinds of information in order to operate effectively. Some of this information is provided directly while other information may be provided or collected from other sources as required by our products and services.

####  What information we collect:

Our website does not collect any information nor ask for registration, and does not use tracking cookies or traffic analysis to store any personally identifiable information. The only personally identifiable information collected from our website is collected from the ‘contact us’ form. Any information attained from this source implies consent for use within the scope of this privacy policy.

PSA does use website traffic logging which enables us to collect anonymous information, but this is limited to completely anonymous information about your browser type and language.

####  How we use Personal Information:

PSA uses the information we collect to improve our products and services and to respond to requests about products and services offered.

PSA also provides a mailing alert facility for which we collect names and email addresses. This information is kept securely and used only to provide the requested service. We will never transfer, sell or make available to any others this information except as outlined in this privacy policy. We provide functionality for users to cancel this service at any time and once cancelled all associated data is also removed.

PSA tracks click behaviour in the e-mails it sends out. This data is collected using clear gifs, tiny invisible images with a unique ID. This data is used to update specific user-profile information, ascertain the topics of most interest to opt-in e-mail recipients, and to generate statistics for internal usage only. These records and any statistics generated are for internal usage only and will not be shared with any third party.

As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information to analyse trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link automatically-collected data through the use of Cookies and log files to personally identifiable information.

####    
Secure Communications

PSA will take reasonable precautions to protect personal information in its possession from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.  
If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can send an e-mail through our website with "Web Site Security Query" in the subject line.

####    
Use of Third Party Services

PSA contracts with select third parties in connection with the delivery of services to our clients. These third parties may not use any personally identifiable information other than to provide the specific contracted services.

####  Links to Other Sites

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of PSA. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any website you visit.

####    
Terms

No company other than PSA is allowed to access information stored on our servers, unless expressly authorized by PSA. Unauthorized access to this information is a violation of the law. PSA has placed security measures and firewalls on all network servers in an attempt to prevent outside parties from accessing private information. In the event of a breach of security, PSA will use legal recourse  to the fullest extent possible against those parties illegally accessing information on our servers.

####  Safe Harbor and EU Privacy Law

As PSA is neither a US nor EU based company we cannot be certified nor attain Safe Harbor status however as PSA is a global company we voluntarily commit to attaining and maintaining a Safe Harbor equivalent standard of Data Privacy. We adhere to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program please visit http://www.export.gov/safeharbor.

####    
Access to Personal Information

Upon request by mail or e-mail (to the addresses noted below in the Contact Information section), PSA will grant individuals reasonable access to personal information that it holds about them, unless otherwise legally unable to do so. In addition, PSA will take reasonable steps to permit individuals to correct, amend, or delete information that is demonstrated to be inaccurate or incomplete. PSA shall provide a response to an access request within 30 days of receiving such request.

We will retain your information for as long as needed to provide services to your organization. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements and then ensure all information is securely deleted.

####  Disclosure Pursuant to Judicial or Government Subpoenas, Warrants or Orders

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us.

####    
Business Transfer

In the event PSA goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via prominent notice on our Web site for a period of at least 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information

####    
Breach of Privacy Policy

If you have received unwanted, unsolicited e-mail sent by PSA or from any PSA or purporting to be sent via PSA, please forward a copy of that e-mail with your comments to [info@psagroup.com](mailto:info@psagroup.com) for review.

####    
Contact Information

Questions or comments regarding this Policy should be submitted to PSA by mail at the following address or via e-mail at [info@psagroup.com](mailto:info@psagroup.com):

**C/O Data Coordinator/COO,**  
PSA Manila, Philippines  
Suite 6, Level 36, Tower 1, The Enterprise Center,  
6766 Ayala Avenue corner Paseo de Roxas,  
Makati City 1226, Philippines

####  Changes to This Privacy Policy

Any updates or changes to our privacy statement will be posted to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by e-mail, or by means of a notice on our home page.
